Louis Contant

SUMMARY

Hi! I'm Louis, a software developer that really likes hard problems to solve. I'm also good at communicating with technical and non technical people which I think is a huge asset in this field. With 5 years of experience on a variety of projects, I'm hoping to be a great addition to your team!

EXPERIENCE

Radio-Canada Senior software developer Dec 2020 — Present

- Lead a major rework of a WinForms application for onair live closed captioning
- Recognized as the go-to problem solver on difficult issues
- Developed and deployed many applications from scratch in C# .NET (backend) and Angular(frontend)
- Responsible for billing system for broadcast rights distribution
- Tech stack: Winform, C#, Angular, .NET 8 ,dotnet core, python, Oracle PLSQL, HTML, Javascript, Typescript

Bonlook

Software developer (internship)

Aug 2019 — Dec 2019

- Handled technical discussions with Sezzle to resolve issues with the integration of their payment and widget
- Created a top to bottom automatic deployment system in AWS with Terraform and Node.js linked to our bitbucket repo
- Maintained python backend
- Tech stack: PHP, Angular, Javascript, NodeJs, Typescript, python, docker, terraform, serverless, AWS, aws lambda

Radio-Canada (CBC)

Software developer (internship)

Jan 2017 — Apr 2017

- Created a new application to interact securely with unsecured PTZ cameras
- Refactored major application for election coverage
- Developed full stack applications in Angular and C# .NET
- Tech stack: Angular, Javascript, Typescript, C#, .NET Framework , dotnet core, python, Oracle PLSQL, HTML

EXO Software developer

Feb 2016 — Aug 2016

- Developed new features and fixed bugs on client facing website in C# .NET and ASP MVC .NET
- Direct internal client communication
- Drafting of comprehensive documentation and processes for the transition from AMT to EXO
- Main developer on the automatic billing system for train cards
- Tech stack: C# .NET, ASP MVC .NET, SQL Server, HTML, CSS, Javascript

PROJECTS

- **doormonster.tv:** Developing a full subscription platform with Java Spring boot and Angular 2+. Deployment system with Docker Compose.
- **Twitch Integrator:** Developing a plugin that facilitates the integration of twitch chat interactions through easy to use event nodes made in C++.

EDUCATION

ÉTS (École de technologie supérieure)

Bachelor degree - Software engineering

Collège Bois-de-Boulogne

DEC - Technique informatique : profil de gestion

Collège Mont-Saint-Louis

Diploma - High school